# Maathusan Rajendram

**PROGRAM** 3A Systems Design Engineering **CELL** (519) 574-0728 • **E-MAIL** mrajendr@uwaterloo.ca



#### **PROFILE**

Strong understanding of object-oriented programming concepts and their application.

Love the startup culture and working in an extremely fast-paced environment; from previous co-op experiences.

Great communication, presentation and interpersonal skills.

Perfectionist for user interface and design; detail-oriented.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **Candidate for Bachelor of Applied Science**

Systems Design Engineering, University of Waterloo, Waterloo, ON September 2012-present

#### SKILLS

Objective - C Java Swift HTML

Java Ruby on Rails HTML/CSS PHP/SQL

C#/C++
JavaScript/jQuery

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Software Developer**

**Knowroaming Ltd** • Toronto, Ontario • December 2014 – May 2015

Lead developer in company's main iOS app. Implemented new features such as RSA encryption authentication and more. Took the initiative to optimize current product packaging. Reduced its size by over 50% thus, saving enormous costs in both shipping and manufacturing. Developed user features in web app using JavaScript to mimic iOS app.

#### **API Developer**

**ERA Environmental Consulting • Montreal, Quebec • April 2014 – August 2014** 

Created a WCF REST web service in C# for apps to communicate with a MS SQL Server. Created and deployed two iOS 7 universal apps that use the above API, into the AppStore (<a href="see website">see website</a>). Worked on and deployed an iPad app via In-house distribution. Worked on a Ruby on Rails web service that connected the iPad app to a PostgreSQL database.

## **Software Engineer - iOS**

Sangriya Inc. • Brampton, Ontario • August 2013 – February 2014

Created an iOS 7 app with search, chat, notification, Facebook login features and more; from conception. Contributed to marketing and analytic analysis. Made use of Facebook API's, Parse platform, Testflight, Crashlytics and Mixpanel.

#### **Program Management**

**Toronto Hydro** • Toronto, Ontario • January 2013 – May 2013

Used thorough knowledge of SQL, VBA, normalization and UI development to create a relational database in a MS Access environment. Acquired presentation and communication skills from presenting program management issues in front of project manager and his team.

#### **Marketing Representative**

**Student Works Painting •** Waterloo, Ontario • May 2013 – August 2013

Utilized excellent communication and marketing skills to make door-to-door sales. Acquired amazing marketing techniques from training sessions. Gained amazing time management and organizational skills from balancing two parttime jobs and school work.

#### PROJECTS (see website)

#### TellMe

## Loblaws eCommerce Winner Best Health App Winner Generated 100% Profit

### FitnessCoach

- At UofT Hacks 2015
   At BrickHacks 2015
- Backed by MongoDB
   Uses Twilio and Mashape
   Android app with Twilio
   Uses Pebble and Myo
   Sales from online ad
   Door-to-door marketing

#### **Chair Business**

- Self-started at age 18

#### VOLUNTEER

#### **Charity Gift Wrapping Supervisor**

**Epilepsy Halton Peel Hamilton** • Brampton, Ontario • November 2014 – January 2015 Promoted from volunteer to supervisor within two weeks. Successfully lead and was responsible for a team of over 20 volunteers.

#### **Tutor**

Club Garcons et Filles de LaSalle • Montreal, Quebec • April 2014 – June 2014

Tutored student ranging from the ages of 9 to 16 in Mathematics, Science and English. Improved my communication skills in French.

#### Chefs Assistant

Robin des Bois • Montreal, Quebec • June 2014 – August 2014

Helped prepare ingredients and assisted in all prep work for the dishes. Improved my communication skills in French.